tepco.co.jp 2019-06-01

# Privacy Policy | TEPCO

## Basic Policy for the Handling of Personal Information

April 1, 2016  
Tokyo Electric Power Company Holdings, Inc.

Tokyo Electric Power Company Holdings, Inc. ("the Company" hereinafter) believes that the proper handling of personal information and the protection of such information is an important social responsibility, and we handle all personal information in a proper manner according to the policy stipulated below in order to fulfill this responsibility.

### 1\. Compliance with Laws and Regulations, etc.

The Company shall comply with all laws and regulations, guidelines of relevant authorities, company rules, and other stipulations for the handling of personal information.

### 2\. Acquisition and Use of Personal Information

The Company shall acquire and use personal information such as names, addresses, and telephone numbers in order to perform its business operations in a proper and uninterrupted manner.  
Acquisition of such personal information shall be performed by legal and fair methods and procedures, and the acquired information shall be used within the scope necessary to perform the Company's business operations in a proper and uninterrupted manner.  
Persons who do not require information on the Company's products and services, etc. may request to stop receiving such information.

### 3\. Ensuring the Safety and Accuracy of Personal Information

The Company shall take the measures necessary in order to prevent leakage, loss, damage, unauthorized access, or other incidents involving personal information, and shall conduct appropriate personal information management.  
The Company shall endeavor to ensure that the personal information in its possession is accurate and up to date within the scope necessary to achieve the purpose of its use.

### 4\. Disclosure and Provision to Third Parties

The Company shall not disclose or provide personal information to third parties except in the following cases.

  * The consent of the individual concerned has been obtained.
  * Such disclosure or provision is urgent and necessary in order to protect human life and health or property, and obtaining the consent of the individual concerned is difficult.
  * It is necessary to cooperate with a national government agency, local government body, or a person entrusted with duties by the aforementioned in performing affairs prescribed by laws and regulations, where obtaining the consent of the individual concerned will impede the execution of the affairs.
  * Personal information is provided as part of business succession.
  * Personal information is disclosed or provided to a contractor within the scope necessary to achieve the purpose of its use. In this case, necessary and appropriate supervision shall be carried out in order to ensure that this contractor handles personal information properly, by means such as concluding an agreement related to the handling of personal information.
  * Other cases where disclosure or provision to a third party is permitted based on laws and regulations, etc.

### 5\. Shared Use

The Company shall only share personal data for use as stipulated below.

#### [Integrated Business Management and Internal Controls of the TEPCO Group]

  * (1)

Scope of Shared Users  
Tokyo Electric Power Company Holdings, Inc.  
TEPCO Fuel & Power, Inc.  
TEPCO Power Grid, Incorporated  
TEPCO Energy Partner, Incorporated

  * (2)

Purposes of Shared Use  
For exercising rights and performing duties based on the integrated compliance of the TEPCO Group, business management and internal controls (such as risk management), and laws and regulations  
However, areas affecting the regulations of the Electricity Business Act are excluded.

  * (3)

Information Items Subject to Shared Use  
Names, addresses, phone numbers, occupations, e-mail addresses, contract information

  * (4)

Persons Responsible for Management of Shared Use  
The Company

#### [Integrated Transaction Accounting Processing of the TEPCO Group]

  * (1)

Scope of Shared Users  
Companies among the TEPCO Group using the group-wide accounting processing services

  * (2)

Purposes of Shared Use  
For integrated transaction accounting processing of the TEPCO Group

  * (3)

Information Items Subject to Shared Use  
Names, addresses, phone numbers, fax numbers, company/organization names, affiliated department, position, bank account information

  * (4)

Persons Responsible for Management of Shared Use  
The Company

### 6\. Disclosure and Correction, etc. of Personal Information

An individual may request disclosure of his/her personal information. It first must be confirmed that the request is from the individual concerned, after which the Company shall endeavor to promptly disclose the information based on laws and regulations, etc. However disclosure may not be possible in the following cases.

  * There is a risk of harm to the life, body, property, or other rights of a third party.
  * There is a risk of significant impediments to the business operations of the Company.
  * Doing so would be in violation of laws or regulations, etc.
  * The request for disclosure is not made in accordance with the procedures established by the Company.

In cases such as when the contents of personal information in the possession of the Company are inconsistent with the facts, the Company shall correct, delete, or take other action within the scope necessary for the Company's business operations based on a request from the individual concerned.

### 7\. Improving Internal Systems

The Company shall provide in-house training and education to our directors, full-time employees, temporary employees, contracted workers, part-time employees, and other personnel in order for them to comply with laws and regulations, guidelines of relevant authorities, company rules, and other stipulations for the handling of personal information.  
The Company shall assign personnel to supervise the management of personal information and periodically perform internal audits in order to properly manage personal information.

### 8\. Improving Measures

When laws are revised or other changes occur, the Company shall endeavor to review and improve the above measures as necessary.  
In the event that the Company reviews the above measures and revises this Policy, we shall provide notice of the revised content on this web page.

## Use Purposes of Personal Information at the Company

April 1, 2016  
Tokyo Electric Power Company Holdings, Inc.

The Company publicly declares that the specific use purposes of personal information in its possession shall be used according to the following.

The Company shall use personal information in its possession within the scope necessary for the following purposes in relation to the business operations listed below indicated in the Company's articles of incorporation: Contract signing and execution, after-service, facilities maintenance and repair, questionnaires, improving and developing our products and services, sending/soliciting/sales of advertising and publicity materials related to our products and services, legally required business operations, as well all other business operations incidental to these.  
However, thorough attention shall be given to maintaining fair competition when using this personal information.  
Persons who do not want to receive questionnaires from the Company, direct mail related to our products and services, and other notifications may request to stop receiving such materials.

  * Electric power business
  * Gas business
  * Manufacture, sales, leasing, installation, operation, and maintenance of facilities, machinery, and devices related to energy
  * Heat provision business
  * Development, mining, processing, sales, and transport of energy resources
  * Sales, renting, and management of real estate, and warehousing operations
  * Planning, design, supervision, construction, and contracting related to building construction, public works construction, and urban and regional development
  * Lending of money
  * Waste treatment and recycling
  * Engineering, consulting, and sales of technology, know-how and information related to the above business operations and environmental conservation
  * Business operations ancillary to the above-indicated

End of document

## Procedures for Disclosing, Correcting, Stopping Use, and Obtaining Notification of the Use-Purpose of Personal Information

April 1, 2016  
Tokyo Electric Power Company Holdings, Inc.

### 1\. Disclosure of Personal Information

You may request the Company to disclose personal information if you want to know the content of your personal information possessed by the Company.

#### (1) Persons Who May Request Disclosure

In general, the person corresponding to the information ("individual concerned") may make a request. In some cases, another person may request the disclosure of personal information in place of the individual concerned, such as in the case of a representative authorized by the individual concerned ("appointed representative" hereinafter) or a legal representative of a minor or adult ward.

#### (2) Disclosure Request Procedures and Reception Desk

Fill in the required items of the "Request for Disclosure of Personal Information" and submit it to the nearest office of TEPCO Power Grid. Provide an original copy of the documents indicated below in order to verify the identity of the individual concerned who is making the request and other purposes. If you want to request disclosure by mail, attach copies of the documents indicated below to the application and send them to the nearest office of TEPCO Power Grid.

##### If the individual concerned is requesting disclosure of personal information:

  * Personal identification of the individual concerned (driver's license, passport, health insurance card)

##### If a representative is requesting disclosure of personal information:

  * Personal identification of the representative (driver's license, passport, health insurance card)
  * Documents proving the qualifications of the representative (Appointed representative: Authorization letter and seal registration certificate or copy of identification of the individual concerned requesting disclosure; Legal representative: Certified copy or extract of the family register, and certificate of registered information of guardian of adult)

**Persons who wish to request disclosure by mail must attach a copy of the following documents showing his/her name and current address.**

Driver's license | Attach a copy of the back side if the address or other information has changed.  
---|---  
Passport | Attach a copy of the page showing your photograph and address.  
Health insurance card | If your address is not indicated or has changed, write your current address on the card and then make a copy to be attached.  
  
*Inquiries such as those regarding electricity for the current month or estimated billing amount are performed in the conventional manner, as these can be handled by telephone. Contact the nearest customer center of TEPCO Energy Partner.

#### (3) The Company's Handling of Disclosure Requests

##### Decision whether to perform disclosure

The Company shall generally make a decision regarding the disclosure of personal information within two weeks after a request for disclosing personal information is received, and the person making the request shall be informed of this decision. However, this time period might be extended for a valid reason such as when clerical procedure processing makes it difficult to comply with such timing. Items subject to disclosure by the Company shall be limited to "retained personal data" as defined in Article 2, Section 5 of the Act on the Protection of Personal Information.

##### Performance of disclosure

The reply letter will be sent by mail to the address of individual concerned except in cases where a representative has made the disclosure request in person at one of the offices, or where the authorization letter indicates that the disclosure request is to be sent to the representative.

##### If disclosure cannot be performed

The Company might not be able to provide full or partial disclosure of personal information in the cases indicated below. The reason will be indicated in such cases.

  * There is a risk of harm to the life, body, property, or other rights of a third party.
  * There is a risk of significant impediments to the business operations of the Company.
  * Doing so would be in violation of laws or regulations, etc.
  * The type and scope of the personal information is not designated as being subject to a disclosure request.
  * The Company does not possess any retained personal data corresponding to the individual concerned.
  * Required items of the "Request for Disclosure of Personal Information" have not been filled in.
  * The identity of the individual concerned or qualifications of the representative cannot be confirmed due to insufficient documents to confirm the individual concerned or prove the qualifications of the representative.
  * The Company's reply letter could not be delivered for two months or more.
  * Other cases such as when the Company has no responsibility for disclosure according to laws or regulations, etc.

### 2\. Correction, Addition, and Deletion of Personal Information

You may request the Company to correct, add to, or delete ("correct, etc." hereinafter) your personal information if you feel that the content of your personal information is not factual.  
In such cases, the Company shall correct, etc. the content so that it is factual within the scope necessary to perform our business operations.  
The Company shall inform you of the content corrected, etc. if correction, etc. is performed, and inform you of the reason if not corrected, etc. 

#### (1) Persons Who May Request Correction, etc.

In general, the person corresponding to the information ("individual concerned") may make a request. In some cases, an appointed representative or legal representative may request the correction, etc. related to personal information in place of the individual concerned.

#### (2) Correction, etc. Request Procedures and Reception Desk

Contact the nearest customer center of TEPCO Energy Partner. You may make a request by mail.

##### If a representative is requesting correction, etc. related to personal information:

Please send both of the following documents.

  * Personal identification of the representative (driver's license, passport, health insurance card)  
* For details regarding attached documents, refer to "1. (2) Disclosure Request Procedures and Reception Desk".
  * Documents proving the qualifications of the representative (Appointed representative: Authorization letter and seal registration certificate or copy of identification of the individual concerned requesting disclosure; Legal representative: Certified copy or extract of the family register, and certificate of registered information of guardian of adult)

### 3\. Stopping Use and Complete Deletion of Personal Information

You may request the Company to stop using or completely delete ("stop using, etc." hereinafter) your personal information if you feel that the Company has acquired or used the information in a manner that violates laws or regulations. In such cases, the Company will perform the required investigation and stop using, etc. the personal information within the scope stipulated by laws and regulations, etc. if a legal violation is confirmed. The Company shall inform you of the stopped use, etc. if we stop using, etc. the information, and inform you of the reason if we do not stop using, etc. the information.

#### (1) Persons Who May Request to Stop Using, etc.

In general, the person corresponding to the information ("individual concerned") may make a request. In some cases, an appointed representative or legal representative may request to stop using, etc. personal information in place of the individual concerned.

#### (2) Stop Using, etc. Request Procedures and Reception Desk

Contact the nearest customer center of TEPCO Energy Partner. You may make a request by mail.

##### If a representative is requesting correction, etc. related to personal information:

Please send both of the following documents.

  * Personal identification of the representative (driver's license, passport, health insurance card)  
* For details regarding attached documents, refer to "1. (2) Disclosure Request Procedures and Reception Desk".
  * Documents proving the qualifications of the representative (Appointed representative: Authorization letter and seal registration certificate or copy of identification of the individual concerned requesting disclosure; Legal representative: Certified copy or extract of the family register, and certificate of registered information of guardian of adult)

### 4\. Informing of the Use Purpose of Personal Information

You may request the Company to inform you of the use purpose of your personal information if you want to know the use purpose of your personal information possessed by the Company. In such cases, the Company shall make every effort to promptly inform you of the legally defined use purpose. However, use purposes informed in such notification by the Company shall be limited to "retained personal data" as defined in Article 2, Section 5 of the Act on the Protection of Personal Information.

#### (1) Persons Who May Request to Be Informed of the Use Purpose

In general, the person corresponding to the information ("individual concerned") may make a request. In some cases, an appointed representative or legal representative may request to be informed of the use purpose of personal information in place of the individual concerned.

#### (2) Use Purpose Notification Request Procedures and Reception Desk

Contact the nearest customer center of TEPCO Energy Partner. You may make a request by mail.

##### If a representative is requesting correction, etc. related to personal information:

Please send both of the following documents.

  * Personal identification of the representative (driver's license, passport, health insurance card)  
* For details regarding attached documents, refer to "1. (2) Disclosure Request Procedures and Reception Desk". 
  * Documents proving the qualifications of the representative (Appointed representative: Authorization letter and seal registration certificate; Legal representative: Certified copy or extract of the family register, and certificate of registered information of guardian of adult)

End of document
